恐怖怪谈前情提要
Previously on Penny Dreadful...
她的天赋令她容易受到伤害
Her gifts make her vulnerable.
他们都将她变得令人垂涎
They also make her desirable.
瓦内萨
Vanessa...
救我
Help me.
米娜怎么了
What happened to Mina?
她与一种生物牵扯到了一块儿
She became embroiled with a creature.
现在她成了他的奴隶
Now she has become his slave,
在他的世界和我们的世界之间徘徊
hovering between our world and his.
它们全都在我身边
They are all about me.
那你在里面做什么
And what's your part in all this?
我只做我分内的事
My part is my own.
我有个儿子死在了非洲
I lost a son in Africa.
我的爸爸 让我跟你一起
Father mine, let me come with you.
视频字幕由 SSK字幕组 制作发布
字幕只供学习 请勿做任何商业行为
敬请关注新浪微博@SSK字幕组
我会证明自己是一个出色的冒险家
I'll prove myself a proper explorer.
彼特是爱你的 爸爸
Peter loves you, Father.
阿蒙内特 女孩
Amunet, girl?
不 老的那个
No, much older.
翻译：琪琪  慕斯 濯涟  呆毛  柯小南
阿蒙内特是太阳神阿蒙拉的配偶
Amunet was the consort of Amun-Ra,
最初的蛇王子
the original serpent prince.
他通过吸食别的灵魂
He was sustained by feeding
来维持生命
on the souls of others.
校对：慕斯  柯小南
我不会把这些告知艾维斯夫人的
I would not tell Miss Ives this.
谁想要知道他们被邪恶势力追捕
Who wants to know they're hunted by the devil?
发生了什么
What's happened?
它追寻你而来
It came after you.
我认为这完全是场计谋
I think it was all a ploy.
但是是米娜把我引荐给他的
But it was Mina who led me to him.
后期：hhjie
她可能是你的敌人
That she may be your enemy.
你能责怪她吗
Can you blame her?
瓦内萨在哪
Where's Vanessa?
我想要我的母亲
I want Mother.
你为什么想要她
Why do you want her?
为什么每个人都想要她
Why does everyone want her?
时间轴：阿黎
要不是我的罪过 这一切都还会发生吗
But for my transgression, would any of this have occurred?
我们不能改变过去
We cannot unmake the past.
我们只能负罪而活 你和我
We shall live with our guilt, you and I.
总监：柯小南
我最亲爱的米娜
My dearest Mina,
我亲爱的朋友
my darling friend.
我康复之后就开始写这封信
I began these letters when I recovered from my illness.
刚开始的时候 我大概每个月写一封
At first, I composed them perhaps every month.
然后每周 到现在每天
Then weekly and now daily.
能确定的是 我很快就会推掉其他所有的工作
Soon I will, no doubt, give up all other occupation
只专注于写作
and simply write.
一封信的结尾会成为下一封信的开头
The ending of one letter becoming the beginning of the next,
接连着的 无止尽的文字
an endless ribbon of words.
我希望有一天你会回复我的信
I write in hope that one day you will answer me
然后一切都可以像以前一样了
and that everything can again be like it was...
即使我知道那已不可能了
Though I know that can never be.
我已经不记得我们小时候天边的云
I don't remember clouds when we were young.
现在还有吗 我最亲爱的米娜
Were there any, my dearest Mina?
或许 只是在远处的地平线上
Just beyond the horizon, perhaps?
还是 全是海岸和沙滩
Or was it all seashore and sandcastles?
我知道这种想法很幼稚
Such a thought is naive, I know.
但是回忆不都是那样的吗
But aren't memories always that?
我们再往里面跑一点 到很远很远的地方
Let's go in and go terribly far out.
不行 我们会被困住的
We mustn't. We'll get in trouble.
你害怕了
You're afraid.
-不 我才没有 -那就跟我一起来
-No, I'm not. -Then come in with me.
你觉得我们能游多远
How far do you think we could swim?
我们想游多远就多远 去到任何地方
Far as we want. Everywhere.
我们到那里以后要去做点什么
And what would we do when we got there?
任何事都行
Everything.
我觉得我们应该跑到我们所能看到的地方那么远
I think we should go in and go as far out as we can see.
不 不行
No, we shouldn't.
你一直这么小心谨慎吗 我的米娜
Will you always be afraid, Mina mine?
还有比我们两家更亲近的吗
Were ever two families closer than ours?
我不记得我们两家之间的门有关上的时候
I don't remember a day that gate between our homes was closed.
直到有一天它永远关上了
Until the day it closed forever.
你好 穆雷夫人 归家的好日子
Hello, Mrs. Murray. Gorgeous day for the homecoming.
我们都在六楼和七楼
We're all at sixes and sevens.
孩子们在阳光房里
Children are in the solarium.
早上好 安德鲁斯先生
Good morning, Mr. Andrews.
早上好
Good morning.
早上好 彼得
Good morning, Peter.
天啊 还是那只猴子吗
God, still at that monkey?
我不管怎么试 它看起来就是
As much as I try, it just looks...
-死了 -是他 不是 它
- Dead. - He's not an "It,"
他是有生命的
he's a "He."
给他取个名字吧
Give him a name.
小瓦 他是一只愚蠢的死猴子
Van, he's a stupid dead monkey.
你必须得给他们取名字
You have to give them names
不然他们永远不会活过来
or they'll never come to life.
它就像一位女巫的咒语
It's like a witch's spell.
这里来自莎士比亚笔下的阿里尔
This is Ariel from the Shakespeare.
你永远
You're forever
都在研究吃其他物种的生物
working on things that eat other things.
我觉得你很残忍
I think you're bloodthirsty.
我很残忍 她只是令人毛骨悚然
I'm bloodthirsty. She's just ghoulish.
我觉得安德鲁斯先生有着最茂密的胡子
I think Mr. Andrews has the most luxurious mustaches.
-我知道 他棒极了 -而且还很高
- I know, he's gorgeous. - And so tall.
我肯定会跟一个长得高的男人结婚
I'm sure I'll marry a tall man.
我不可能爱上一个二等残废
I couldn't love someone stunted,
不然舞会上一定会很尴尬的
it'd be too embarrassing at balls.
-他是个什么样的男人 -嗯
- What sort of man will he be? - Hmm...
至少高于六尺
Over 6 feet at least.
长着他每天都抹蜡的胡子
With mustaches he waxes daily
和一双跳舞的小脚
and tiny feet for dancing.
你呢
What about you?
绝不可能是爸爸的可怕律师的一员
Anything but one of father's dreadful solicitors.
当然 你可是要跟彼得结婚的人
Then, of course, you're going to marry Peter.
每个人都这么说
Everyone says so.
我不应该呆在这里跟你结婚 瓦内萨
I shan't be here to marry you, Van.
那你会去哪里
Where will you be?
去非洲跟我爸爸一起
In Africa with father.
你确定你想做一个探险家
Are you sure you want to be an explorer?
我不可能一辈子都摆弄这些猴子标本
Well, I can't be making stuffed monkeys my whole life.
这些包要轻拿轻放
Be careful with those bags.
-父亲 -你好 彼得
- Father! - Hello, Peter.
父亲
Father!
-这儿是我的女孩儿们
- And there's my girl.
你们好
Hello!
你太瘦了
You're so thin.
我都能感觉得到你的肋骨
I can feel your ribs this time.
而且你没有戴帽子
And you haven't worn your hat.
噢 被你们发现了
Oh, you've caught me out.
那是我第一件弄丢的东西
That was the first thing I lost.
-第二件是什么 -我的路
- What was the second? - My way.
你好 格拉迪斯
Hello, Gladys.
别哭了 亲爱的
None of that, dear.
你给我带了什么
What did you bring me?
嗯 让我看看
Well, let's see...
我们有什么
What have we got here?
现在
Now...
呃
Ugh.
-这是什么 -这是薮猫
- What is it? - It's a serval.
来自坦噶尼喀湖湖滨的薮猫
Genus Leptailurus from the shores of Lake Tanganyika.
-好赞啊 -谢谢你 父亲
- How gorgeous. - Thank you, Father.
现在 我都快饿死了
Now, I'm as hungry as a crocodile.
你有没有准备一餐盛宴
Have you put on a proper feast?
打断一下
Excuse me?
我记得最清楚的就是这些归家的节日
Those festive homecomings I remember most.
那才是真正的假期
They were our true holidays.
我父母总是很喜欢你们一同进餐
My mother and father were always welcome company at your table.
你父亲日渐晒黑 每次都会回赠我们稀有的礼物
Your father would return to us with rare gifts and a sunburn.
现在 有谁乐意
Now, would anyone like to
听听我和这些食人族待在一起的遭遇
hear about my encounter with the cannibals?
是吗 好啊
Yes? Good.
但最难得的是他的探险传奇
But rarest of all were his tales of adventure,
我相信一定润色过后才告诉我们的
I'm sure much edited for our ears.
当时我们突然听到一声呼喊
...when we suddenly heard a cry...
尼阿美
Nyame.
彼得的眼睛就会亮起来
Peter's eyes would light up.
他在想象和父亲一起会有多么非凡的未来啊
Such a marvelous future he imagined alongside his father.
我们还没反应过来 就被网住了
Before we knew it we were tangled up
浑身都缠着绳子和网 他们就在那儿
in ropes and nets, and there they were.
大叫着 挥着手中的长矛 唱颂着 Nyame Nyame Nyame
Shouting, waving their spears, chanting, "Nyame! Nyame! Nyame!"
-Nyame是指肉 -噢
- Nyame means "Meat." - Oh!
-新鲜的肉食 也就是我们
- Flesh. Food. Us.
真是可怕
That's just awful.
我们开饭吧
Shall we begin?
要不是我们关系这么亲密 我的米娜
But for all our kinship, my Mina,
我们并不完全相像
we were not completely alike.
天主教堂的神秘感
The mysteries of my Catholic church
是你和你的家人所陌生的
were alien to you and your family.
我要是在大点 会看到更多
Had I been older, I would have seen more.
在这些笑声背后
Beneath the laughter,
在这些交谈甚欢的对话背后
beneath that great, easy outpouring of conversation,
其实有着紧张的暗流涌动
it wasn't tension exactly, was it?
这种感觉并不来自于双方家人
Not amongst two such congenial families.
不是
No.
它更像是某种事物的颤动
It was more a tremor of something.
像是声波在无底洞中传播的微弱颤抖
Like words hollered down a bottomless pit
回声听着会更加闷声且难以捕捉
that come back occluded and more complex.
也许是成长所造就的
Adulthood, maybe.
在那个恐怖的夜晚 一切发生的夜晚
And on that terrible night, that night it happened,
晚餐时发生过什么特别的事么
did anything particularly important happen at the dinner?
不 我印象中没有
No, not that I recall.
老实说 我还以为
Honestly, I thought I was going
我会在下一个转角找到你和彼得
to find you and Peter around the next corner,
你们会藏在角落里吓我
playing some trick on me.
我的母亲
My mother.
你的父亲
Your father.
除了震惊
More than the shock,
这种偷摸的罪恶 不堪的行为
the sinfulness, the forbidden act,
我看在眼里
there was this.
享受其中
I enjoyed it.
好像发现了一些私语
Something whispered.
我偷偷地听着
I listened.
也许它一直存在着
Perhaps it has always been there, this thing,
这魔鬼就住在我体内
this demon inside me.
或等在身后 等待我转身面对
Or behind my back, waiting for me to turn around.
我没告诉你我看到的这些
I didn't tell you what I saw.
要如何启齿
How could I?
没必要让你一夜长大
There was no need for you to grow up so fast.
-明天我们该进城了 -好啊
- Tomorrow, we should go into town. - Yes.
其实你是可以承受的 就像我一样
You could not have endured it. Or so I told myself.
也许我只是为独享这阴暗的罪恶而暗喜
Perhaps I was just cherishing the secrecy of it as a hidden sin.
但我的内心发生了变化
But in me, there was a change.
从树篱迷宫那晚起 我就开始变了
I marked it from that night in the hedge maze.
也许我一直就是这样的人
Perhaps it was always there.
做些小坏事
Little acts of wickedness.
当然是无伤大雅 所有女孩儿都会这样
Harmless, of course. Something any girl would do.
我告诉自己 我只是在淘气
I told myself it was no more than mischief.
却知道 这已远超出淘气
But I knew it was more.
我心里清楚的很
Of course I did.
后来我们长大 你长得越来越可人
And as we grew up, and you grew lovelier,
所以你先遇到真命天子也很正常
it was no wonder to me that you met your gentleman first.
他有着如你期望的浓密胡须
Or that he had luxurious mustaches.
一位英勇而年轻的军官
Such a gallant young officer.
你们是如此的天作之合
What a handsome couple you were.
找到你啦
Found you.
谢谢
Thank you.
彼得那时只有淡淡的胡须
It was the season of Peter's inadequate beard,
我看着你和布兰森上尉的感情日益深厚
I watched your courtship with Captain Branson flourish.
看着你们之间的爱情互动
All the stratagems of advance and retreat.
我一直以为我是更好的那个
I always thought of myself as the stronger one.
但 你是这么的勇敢争取
But here, you were so valiant.
我又怎能不动征服之心
How could he not be conquered?
我觉得你要在那张餐桌旁决定终身了
I think you set your future at that table.
他谈到印度 你突然之间就开口问道
He spoke of India and suddenly I saw you going.
我何时能再见到你
When would I see you again?
印度不是非常遥远吗
Isn't India so terribly far away?
那我要怎么办
What would I do?
嫁给彼得么
Marry Peter?
老天 我多么嫉妒你
God, how I envied you.
我甚至有点恨你
Perhaps I even hated you.
你一向温柔顺从 又怎么可能
How was it possible that you, always so meek and obliging,
怎么可能比我先踏入婚姻的大门
were to have this greatest of adventures before me?
你先去体验爱情 去体验男人的抚摸
You would know love, you would know a man's touch,
而我 一向勇敢如我 却对此一无所知
while I, the courageous one, knew nothing of life.
米娜乖孩子
Mina, my dear.
他是个好男人 这点毋庸置疑
Of course, he's a fine man. I've no doubt of that.
他也会是个称职的丈夫
He'll make a proper husband.
但我不想她远去印度
But I hate to think of her out in India
天气那么热 还有那些印度阿三
with all that heat and those filthy wogs.
你觉得非洲会是什么样子
What do you think Africa will be like?
天啊 莎莎 别提了
Oh, God, Van. Don't mention that.
每次我想和父亲讨论这个问题 他就逃避
Every time I try and talk with father about it, he shies away.
也许你不该提起这个话题
Maybe you shouldn't ask anymore.
这是我的梦想 你知道的
It's all I've ever dreamed about. You know that.
和父亲一起探险
My father and I off on an adventure,
开拓不为人知的密道
blazing some daring new trail.
或许
Perhaps...
或许什么
What?
或许之后 我就不会这么让他失望了
Perhaps then, I wouldn't be such a disappointment to him.
我从未达到过他的期望
I was never the son he wanted.
身体孱弱 不擅长游戏
Always ill, never good at games.
总是让他失望
A disappointment.
他更需要一个像
He needed someone more like...
像我一样的孩子
Me?
我走之后你就孤身一人了
You'll be all alone when I go.
米娜去了印度 我和父亲远行
Mina in India, me with Father.
你会很难过的
That'll be sad for you.
但我想
But I suppose...
牧师7点就到 母亲希望我们到场
The minister's coming at seven and mother wants us there.
你知道她很讨厌迟到
You know how she is about time.
如果我能回到过去
If I could only go back now,
我会追上他 告诉他
I would run after him and say,
别走 别去非洲
"Don't go. Don't go to Africa.
你会死的 身体太弱了
"You'll never survive, you're too weak.
可你弱的那么美 彼得
"You're beautifully weak, Peter.
我爱死了你的孱弱
"I love you for your weakness."
从那一刻起 米娜 我清晰地看到了未来
For at that moment, Mina, I saw the future crystal clear.
那晚我虔诚祈祷 没等来上帝的指示
I tried to pray that night. God didn't answer me.
却得到魔鬼的回答
But another did.
快了 孩子
Soon, child.
好戏即将登场
What games we will have.
那个周末是你最开心的时刻
You were never happier than that weekend.
次日一早你就要举行婚礼
On the following morning you would be married.
作为米娜 穆雷小姐 只得这一晚
One more night as Miss Mina Murray
明天就将成为查尔斯 布兰森夫人
before you became Mrs. Charles Branson.
好的
All right.
拜拜
Bye-bye.
你似乎不在意这样失去自我
You didn't seem to mind this loss of self.
可我却在意
Perhaps I minded it for you.
你找到我了
You've found me out.
最后的单身之夜
Last night of freedom, eh?
你想看些有趣的事么
Would you like to see something interesting?
不
No.
我的米娜
My Mina?
对 你的米娜
Your Mina.
你不用太过惊讶
Although you'll be relieved to know
她只摆弄些温和的动物
she only worked with the most pacific of animals.
这是她的松鼠
- This is her squirrel. -
哪些是你的？
Which are yours?
反正不是温和的动物
Not the docile ones.
意料之中
That doesn't surprise me.
我总觉得想赋予一个生命
I've always felt you have to name a thing
就要先给他起名
before it comes to life,
就像一个咒语
like a witch's spell.
他的名字是阿里尔
His name is Ariel.
最难做的部分是眼睛
The most challenging bit is the eyes.
用玻璃做的
They're glass, of course,
本身是没有生命的
so by nature are dead and dull.
但捕猎者怎么能如此没有生机
But that wouldn't do for my great predator.
所以我在玻璃眼珠后放了镜子 就有了生气
So I put mirrors behind the glass eyes, so they would spark.
看见没
You see?
看上去栩栩如生
It's like they're alive.
他们就是活的
They are.
如果我可以
I would put mirrors
我想在整个世界的背后都放上镜子
behind the entire world if I could.
好了 没事的
There, there.
瓦内莎
Vanessa!
瓦内莎 回来
Vanessa, come back!
-这太淫乱了 你怎么能 -我为什么不能
- This is obscene! You mustn't! - How can I not?
你难道没有羞耻之心吗
Have you no shame?
马上给我滚上楼去
Get upstairs this instant!
你居然还有脸在我面前如此道貌岸然吗
How dare you speak to me of shame?
上楼 向我父亲道歉去
Get upstairs yourself and make amends to my father.
我要见她
I have to see her.
为了什么
To do what?
为了解决问题
Make this right.
从前 我总觉得自己浪迹天涯 远在异乡这么多年
I always thought my traveling would kill my family.
会害了我的家人
Being away so long.
是我太欠考虑了
My thoughtlessness...
我从没想到 会是一个可怕的小姑娘害了他们
I never imagined it would be a cruel little girl.
病症来势汹汹 无可抵挡
When the illness came, it was absolute.
我那时几乎毫无知觉
I was aware of almost nothing.
医生也无法解释发生了什么
The doctors were at a loss to explain it.
因为 你知道的 它本身就是那么的莫名
Because, you see, it was inexplicable.
谢谢 谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
我 我来处理 我来处理
I... I have her. I have her.
你必须吃点东西
You must eat.
他们发现那其实并不是癫痫
They don't think it's epilepsy anymore.
我告诉过你了吗
Did I tell you that?
金斯顿医生不知道要从何下手
Dr. Kingston doesn't know what to think.
那个古怪的小个子
Ridiculous little man.
他们害怕
They fear...
他们害怕的是 或许是你的大脑
They fear that, perhaps, it's your brain...
有什么东西侵入了
Something inside you.
还有么
What else...
还有 啊 米娜走了
What else? Um, Mina's gone.
她不想待在这儿了
She didn't want to stay here.
大概我们不该谈论她
Should we not talk of Mina?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们不跟穆雷家的人说话 他们也不跟我们交流
We don't talk to the Murrays, or they to us.
我尝试过去那儿
I tried going over there.
但他们每次都拒我于门外
I was not welcome.
马尔 马尔科姆先生
Sir Mal... Sir Malcolm...
亲爱的 他们不知道你身上发生了什么
They don't know what's wrong with you, darling.
你的病发作时
The seizures...
发作的时候真是太可怕了
The seizures are so terrible.
我们应该咨询一下伦敦的专家
We shall be consulting a specialist in London.
你一向很喜欢伦敦
You always liked London.
所以 说不定会有所好转
So, perhaps the change...
我们在斯特兰德大街预订了房间
We've booked rooms at the Strand.
在那里
There's a...
在那里有一个声名远播的诊所
There's a clinic nearby that are well known
专为治疗女性心理失常的
for treating women's disorders.
一个精神病院
An asylum.
妈妈 我没疯
I am not mad, Mother.
我不是不开心
I am not unhappy.
你应该让我去死的
You should let me die.
瓦内萨
Vanessa,
你听懂我说的了吗
do you understand what I've said?
我觉得你最好待在外面 艾弗斯夫人
I think it best if you stepped outside, Mrs. Ives.
我哪儿也不去
I'll stay.
我有些话想向你的丈夫说清楚
I must speak frankly to your husband.
我想待在这儿
I'd like to stay.
这种紧张性精神分裂 我也略有耳闻
This form of catatonia is not unknown to me.
这些异常的生理损耗说明
The unusual physical exertions are manifestations of...
这不是正常损耗
They were not exertions.
她在经受着折磨
She was being tormented.
我见过癫痫发作时
I have seen epileptic seizures
能导致骨折的状况 艾弗斯夫人
that have broken bones, Mrs. Ives.
并不是不可能 只是非常罕见
None of this impossible, just rare.
精神性导致的癔症并非无药可医
Hysteria of a psychosexual nature can be treated.
治疗时需要用到麻醉剂
The treatments involve narcotics
和不断增加强度的水疗
and escalating hydrotherapy.
冷水将会通过减缓大脑的供血循环
Cold water reduces circulation to the brain,
来降低新陈代谢的速度和身体的机动性
thereby reducing the metabolism and motor activity.
焦虑反应和精神创伤将会减缓
The agitation and mental trauma will slow
最后中止
and then cease.
我亲眼看到过它的疗效 艾弗斯先生 你不用有所疑虑
I've seen it work, Mr. Ives, you can have no doubt.
那如果它不起作用呢
And what if it doesn't work?
如果没有起色的话
If we see no improvement,
我们还可以选择进行手术
there are surgical options open to us.
好的
Yes.
那就这么办吧
Let's do that.
艾弗斯先生 艾弗斯夫人 请即刻离开这里
Mr. And Mrs. Ives, please leave the room immediately.
听到你开口真好 瓦内萨
It is very good to hear your voice, Vanessa.
我是克里斯朵夫 班宁医生 我是来帮你的
I'm Dr. Christopher Banning and I hope to help you.
你的父母
Your parents have...
我想离开这里
I want to be out there.
你会的
You will be.
我们有一个很可爱的小花园
We have a lovely garden that...
我更喜欢海洋
I prefer the ocean.
你见过溺水的人吗
Have you seen someone who's drowned?
我见过
I have.
不是什么猫啊狗的
Not a dog or a cat.
它们连灵魂都没有
Not enough soul in a dog or a cat.
我是说 一个人
I mean a man.
一百个人
A hundred men.
一艘奴隶贩运船
A slave ship.
是的 就是那样
Yes. More than anything.
直挺挺地沉下去 而那些人们还被锁链禁锢着
Pulled right down, with the men still chained.
那些经受着痛苦的灵魂 如今又要忍受更重的折磨
Souls in torment who now find themselves in greater torment.
你见过那个场景吗 克里斯朵夫 马修 班宁医生
Have you seen that, Dr. Christopher Matthew Banning?
瓦内萨 现在你得坐下来
Vanessa, it's very important to me that you sit down now.
瓦内萨是谁
Who's Vanessa?
艾弗斯夫人 我能进来吗
Mrs. Ives, may I step in?
当然
Of course.
艾弗斯先生
Mr. Ives.
皮特
Peter.
我是过来道别的
I've come to say goodbye.
我 我将和我爸一起去非洲了
I'm, um, off to Africa with my father.
-我可以看她吗 -我
- May I see her? - I...
-可以 -并不觉得
- Yes. - ...don't think...
在这呆着
Stay here.
你
You...
你千万不要感到震惊
You mustn't be shocked.
她改变了太多了
She's much changed.
瓦瓦
Van...
噢 瓦瓦
Oh, Van...
她会死么
Will she die?
如果上帝存在的话
If there is a God.
她会一直这样么
Is she always like this?
不
No.
疾病还在发作
There are episodes of activity.
我能过去陪陪她吗
May I sit with her?
当然可以
Yes. Of course.
她还认识我吗
Does she know me?
我不知道
We don't know.
但是和她聊聊吧 对她也是一种帮助
But talk to her, it's meant to help.
瓦瓦
Hello, Van.
我是皮特啊
It's Peter.
我觉得你再近一点吧
Closer, I'm afraid.
我是皮特啊
It's Peter.
我将要去非洲了
I'm off to Africa.
你能相信么
Can you believe it?
我最终还是开始了这场我们说过的冒险
Finally having that adventure we talked about.
很激动啊
Very excited.
我昨天沿着我们之前游泳的海岸
I walked by the shore yesterday
散步了
where we used to swim.
你应该吻我的
You should have kissed me.
你现在会吻我吗
Will you kiss me now?
你会在那儿死掉的
You're going to die there.
你会在那儿死去的
皮特
Peter.
祝你一路顺风
Good luck on your trip.
谢谢你来看她
And thank you for coming.
没事的
Of course.
皮特
Peter,
他对你说了什么
what did she say to you?
我没听懂
I couldn't make her out.
你认识济慈么
Do you know Keats?
那个诗人 就是那个大名鼎鼎的诗人
The poet, I mean, Keats, the poet.
我不能说话
I can't speak.
我太虚弱了
I'm too weak.
不 你并不是
No, you're not.
你不该在这
You are not here.
但是
And yet...
你是谁
Who are you?
你不是马尔科姆先生
You are not Sir Malcolm.
你非要给东西命名才觉得它是活的么
You have to name a thing to make it live, don't you?
那 你是
And shall I name you?
除非你想让我活
Only if you want me to live.
蛇
Serpent.
你是这个意思么
Is that what you mean?
巫师 骗子 黑暗之王
Enchanter, Deceiver, Prince of Darkness, Devil of the Pit?
你就这么瞧不起你的老朋友吗
Have you such contempt for your old friend?
继续 济慈
So, the Keats...
夜莺颂里面有这四句话
Four lines from Ode to a Nightingale
总能和我达到共鸣
have always struck a chord with me.
当济慈写这诗的时候 他濒临死亡
Keats was dying when he wrote them,
而且 他知道他即将死去
and he knew he was dying,
你不觉得这为诗增加了趣味吗
which adds to the piquancy, don't you think?
你要听这四句话吗
Would you like to hear them?
我没得选好吧
Do I have a choice?
听好了 瓦纳萨
Vanessa, please.
你永远都是有选择的
You've always had a choice.
你允许这一切发生的
You allowed all this to happen.
你找到了它又毁了它
Hell, you sought it out and fucked it.
你可以随时关上门
You could have shut the door at any time.
你随时可以
You still can.
就现在 你会吗
Right now. Will you?
是的
Yes.
还要放弃一切我们会拥有的
And give up everything we could have together?
一个人最美好但是也是最罪恶的
The true knowledge of man's virtue, as well as his sin.
就是权力
The power.
这个世界之外的风景
The sight beyond this world.
我对这世界之外别无所求
I want nothing beyond this world.
不要撒谎了
Don't lie to me.
你一直沉溺于深海
You've always been drawn to the deep ocean,
陶醉在黑暗
to the dark whisper,
玻璃眼背后的镜子
a mirror behind the glass eyes.
生命最完整的状态
To life at its fullest.
你能现在关门么
Will you close that door now?
嗯 继续
So, the Keats.
那四句话
The lines from Keats.
听着在
Yes.
我在黑暗中倾听
"Darkling, I listen
多少次
"And, for many a time I
我几乎爱上了静谧的死亡
have been half in love with easeful Death,
我在诗思里用尽了我的言辞
"Call'd him soft names in many a mused rhyme
求他把我的一息散入空茫
"To take into the air my quiet breath."
所以 黑暗回答了
So the darkness spoke.
是的
Yes.
你还听到了
But you listened.
愿克莱尔 艾夫斯
May the soul of Claire Ives
和其他忠诚的灵魂
and the souls of all the faithful
受到上帝的仁慈庇佑
departed through the mercy of God
永保安息
rest in peace.
-阿门 -阿门
- Amen. - Amen.
妹妹
Sister.
我不怪你
I do not blame you.
不管是什么样的罪行
Whatever sin,
在你的苦难折磨中都慢慢会被原谅
it has been forgiven in your suffering.
在如此痛苦的折磨下
So much suffering.
我受到的折磨比我应得的还多
It is more than I deserve,
但我仍然不能原谅我自己
but I can't forgive myself.
想说的太多
There's so much to say.
或者太少
Or so little.
我现在结婚了
I'm married now.
你能想象吗
Can you imagine that?
他是个律师
He's a lawyer,
在埃塞克斯的霍金斯手下工作
in the employ of Mr. Hawkins of Essex.
他并没有像我英勇的布兰森队长
He doesn't have a mustache
一样有小胡子
like my gallant Captain Branson,
但是哈克先生是个好人他也深爱着我
but Mr. Harker's a good man and he loves me.
我为你感到高兴
I'm happy for you.
还有我们可怜的皮特
And our poor Peter.
很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
要是你那天在迷宫里面去追他
If only you had run after him that day in the maze,
然后抱紧他并告诉他不要去
and held him tight, and told him not to go
而且你告诉他你就爱他的孱弱
and that you loved him for his weakness.
你是怎么知道的
How do you know about that?
我现在知道很多事了瓦内萨
I know about many things now, Vanessa.
主告诉我了许多事
The master has taught me much.
那些没人应该知道的事
Things no one should ever know.
救救我
Help me.
把我从头手中就走
Save me from him.
求求你
Please.
米娜需要我们的帮忙
Mina needs our help.
先让我进去可以吗
Will you let me in?
还有其他事儿吗
And there's nothing more?
没了
No.
你认为你还能再接近她
You believe you can reach out to her again?
或者是她接近我
Or she to me.
我知道你不相信
I know you do not credit it.
你可不了解我
You know nothing of me.
你知道我杀过多少人吗
Do you know how many men I've killed?
在非洲我们每一步都踏在血上
In Africa we walked in blood every step.
我曾一度很想杀了你以解心头只恨
There was a time I would gladly have killed you.
也许终有一天我会真的杀了你
There may come a time when I gladly shall.
但是现在来看 我可以好好利用你
But for now, I can make use of you.
-没有了吗 -还有什么吗
- And no more? - What else?
宽恕
Forgiveness?
去你的罗马教堂去找吧 最后你会在那一无所获
Go to your Roman church for that, you'll find none here.
你是否真正的想象过一分钟
Have you imagined for one moment
这对我来说是什么
what this has been for me?
不可被原谅的罪行已经在我的一生中留下了不可磨灭的记号
An unforgivable transgression that has marked me for life.
你认为你在痛苦中煎熬
You think you've suffered.
你认为你在刀尖上嗜血
You think you know blood.
你认为你在生死中浮沉
You think you've walked on corpses.
你将这些丑陋之事隐匿 可我却比你遭受的更多
Spread them from here to the horizon and I have walked further!
你这个软弱 肮脏 好色还有虚荣的男人
You weak, foul, lustful, vainglorious man.
你怎么胆敢擅自跟我聊到死亡
How dare you presume to speak to me of death?
那我们应该一起谈谈
Then we shall speak of it together.
是的
Yes.
我就跟着它找到米娜
We will follow it to Mina.
是的
Yes.
接下来呢
And then?
你大限将至
You will be done.
我继续前行
I will walk on.
我会让塞姆班准备一个房间的
I'll have Sembene prepare a room.
这就是你的家了
This is your home now.
我不期望你对我宽恕
There is no exculpation I expect of you.
我的内疚终是我的 我将与它同行
My guilt is my own and that I carry with me.
它便是我的现在与将来
It is my present and my future.
它已经使我如此短暂的人生糟糕透顶
It has damned me well beyond this short life of mine.
但是在确保你安全之前我将不永不停息
But I will not rest until you are safe.
我人生将再无其他追求
There is no other purpose in my life.
我永远爱你
I shall love you always.
你最亲爱的朋友 瓦内萨
Your dearest friend, Vanessa.
附言
Postscript.
你的父亲很爱你
Your father loves you very much
愿意做一切来拯救你
and would do anything to save you.
但是我对你是另一种哎
But I love you in a different way.
我爱你爱到
I love you enough
可以杀了你
to kill you.